This task is about datatypes.
We have been given a set of types
with constructors above here.
We want to use these constructors down below here
in order to create our values of the given types.
We can use all these constructors here
in order to create a value of a type.
For value1 and value2 we
require a value of type T.
Values of type T can be constructed
using constructors A and B.
So we could construct two values of
type T by saying maybe one is A True.
And we could define the same
value setting again A is True,
of course we are violating the task
here in this case if we do so.
Because it says that we are not allowed to
or we should use every data constructor.
So for a True and a True this
task is not solved correctly.
There is a test suite within this task.
We load the program in ghci.
We have a test suite down below here.
If we execute the test suite then we get a
failure in value1 and value2 are different.
It says that it expected True but got
False, so somehow the values are the same.
And that's not what we want.
We want to have different values and
furthermore we have to use all the constructors.
And all the other tests fail because we
still have 'undefined's in our program.
Okay. So let's switch back to the code here.
In order to fix this and both problems: having
different values and using all the constructors
we have to choose the other constructor here.
Because T is not appearing anywhere else
in value3, value4, value5, value6 or
value7 or any other types U, V, and W!
We have to choose another
constructor: and that's B here.
We can choose the most simple value for B -
which is the empty list - as the first argument.
But we could choose any list of integers here.
If we do this then the first test is fixed.
So the first runs through but we
get errors in the later tests.
Let's focus on the creation of the values here.
Now we have to create a value of type U.
U has two constructors C and D.
So we can choose any of those.
I'm choosing the first one in this case.
So we choose C and then we
have to choose a Boolean.
This can be either True or False.
Let's take False this time here.
And then we need a value of type V
and for V we have two constructors.
In order to create a value of type V we
have to choose one of those constructors.
We enclose the whole expression into brackets
because both constructors
require one argument each.
I just choose E for the first constructor here.
So let's choose E as the constructor and
just any Int value so we can say E 42.
Now we continue with the next value – value4.
This value is a pair of U and V.
So we need to write a pair.
The pair has two arguments.
The first one is a value of type U.
U again is either C or D and in order
to fulfill the requirement here that we
shall choose every data constructor
we will now choose the second one.
So let's choose D here.
And we require another value also for
the V datatype in the first argument.
Let's choose the other constructor
here, so let's say we choose F.
F has one argument.
This argument is a pair of Int and Bool.
So we can write the pair here again.
The first argument of the pair is the Int value.
We can just choose any Int value.
Let's take 5 and another Bool value.
Let's choose True here.
Now we have our first argument of F
and we have our first argument of D
which is the only argument of D.
So we are finished with our first
value of our pair - of the pair U V.
Now we require a V value.
Again we can choose any constructor here.
We can choose E or F.
I choose E here and let's say 12 as Int value.
Important here – which the task also says
– we shall not reuse any subexpressions.
So in this case we should not write E 42.
Just keep E 12 and we're
fine in fulfilling the task.
And now we continue with
value5 which is again a pair.
And this time pair of V and W.
So we write a pair.
Now we require another value of V.
As we've used all the constructors for V already
I can choose again any of the constructors.
I choose the simpler one here.
So I choose E 5 this time.
For W we require to choose one
of these constructors down here.
So we have G, H, and I as constructors.
Let's choose the first one here.
So we have G, and we require a value
of V as the first argument of G.
Again, I choose the simpler
constructor E here and let's say E 2.
Now we have value6, which is again a pair.
This time, a pair of W and U.
So we have a pair, and the
first member of the pair is a W.
We've chosen the G already for W.
Now we just choose another constructor.
I choose this time I.
I has one argument, which is a U.
U has two constructors.
We can choose either of them.
So I choose the simpler
one - the D constructor.
D again has one argument, which is a V.
Now, again, we choose a constructor of V.
We can choose E and F.
I, again, choose the simpler E because all
those constructors are covered as well already.
So we choose E and let's say 1.
We are done with I because we are done
with E, which just had one argument,
so we fulfill the argument of E and we
have also finished the argument for I thus.
So we can continue with the second
argument of the pair, and this is a U.
The U, again, has two constructors.
We've chosen them already.
So I will
choose the second constructor here for the
U, which is the simpler one - so I choose D.
And we shall choose a
value for the first argument, which is a V again.
So we can choose between E and F here.
I will choose an E here, and this time it's 5.
If we want to be even more sure that the program
is not rejected within Autotool because we have
some common subexpression here, we
could also change this one here.
Because it looks quite similar
here – the D (E 1) and D (E 5).
So we could change the other
constructor in one of the cases to a C.
The C has two arguments, so I would change
this one here just to show a different value.
So we could change it into C False (E 5)
or even change the constructor for the V
as well by choosing the F constructor instead of
E, so having a different value there as well.
And now we have to change the
first argument into a pair.
So we could choose 5 and a Boolean
which could be either False or True.
I just take True here.
Now we have a different value.
It's rather easy to exchange values
and exchange constructors to construct
different values for these types.
The last missing is a W.
We could again choose any
of the constructors for W
but as we have three W's here to choose
we should now choose the one that is left.
We chose G already, we chose I, so
we have to choose H in this case
in order to fulfill the requirement.
Now our tests run all through.
And we can also check again that
we used all the constructors.
As the program is compiling, we
know that the types are fitting.
So we constructed values for each of the types.
Otherwise, our program would
be rejected by the compiler.
We can check that we used all the
constructors by simply looking into the code.
For the first type T, we can check that we used
A by just searching within our definition on the
right-hand side of the values – i.e.
what's written after the equal sign.
In this case, we search for A.
We have A here, and we have B here.
So those are covered.
The same we can do for U.
We require C and D as constructors.
We have C here, and we have
D here, so this is covered.
For our V, we require E and F as constructors.
We have E here, and we have F
here, and we have F here as well.
So we're covered basically.
And we require for our W: G,
H, and I are constructors.
We have G here, we have I
here, and we have H here.
So we have covered all the constructors
and fulfilled the task as required.
Again, just as a side note: it's easy
to create more values of the given
types – even different values because
we can change any of the parameters.
For B, for instance, we could
have a different list of Int.
So we could add any list of Int here,
and it would still be a value of type T.
And we can change the Booleans from
False to True and so on and so forth.
So we can basically exchange all
the parameters, the arguments of the constructors
in order to create different values for the types.